Wertheimer, Barbara, Office Files /4015
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Barbara Wertheimer Office Files
1971-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wertheimer, Barbara
/4015
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Includes correspondence, speeches, and publications.
3084551
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 13, 2016
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, February 22, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Barbara Mayer Wertheimer (1926-September 23, 1983) was an American labor historian and labor organizer from the 1940s through the early 1980s.
From 1947 to 1948 Ms. Wertheimer was an organizer and acting education director for the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. She worked briefly for the American Labor Education Service and then from 1961 to 1966 as a consultant for the New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal. In 1966 Ms. Wertheimer joined the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University. While at Cornell she was a senior extension associate, director of the Trade Union Women's Studies program, and, from 1977 on, an associate professor and director of the Institute for Women and Work, which she cofounded. Ms. Wertheimer remained at Cornell until her death in 1983.
Ms. Wertheimer is well known for her monograph "We Were There: The Story of Working Women in America" (1977).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5729: Barbara Wertheimer Research Files 5736: Barbara Wertheimer Additional Files 5736 P: Barbara Wertheimer Photographs 6144: Barbara Wertheimer Additional Files 6144 AV: Barbara Wertheimer Collection of Audio Recordings
Wertheimer, Barbara M.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3084551
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1968-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Barbara Wertheimer, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Unclassified 2, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Unclassified, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Notes and Logs, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Program and Events I, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Course Materials (ILR), 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Speeches by BW, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Correspondence: Anne Nelson, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Programs and Events 2, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Clippings, 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Publications by Others, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Notes and Logs 2 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Publications by BW, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Resumes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Annual Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Correspondence - J. Berk, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- NUEA - Act Meeting, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Region 2: NUEA Nov. 29 Conf. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Region 2: NUEA Nov. 29 Conf. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)